
aws-devops-interview-questions-answers
https://www.upgrad.com/blog/aws-devops-interview-questions-answers/


Getting Started with AWS
http://docs.aws.amazon.com/gettingstarted/latest/awsgsg-intro/gsg-aws-intro.html

<set-theory> set theory
	<h8y> -General
	
	why AWS services? whats the motivation behind using aws services?
	on-demand computing resources and services
	pay-as-you-go pricing - you pay only for what you use
	no upfront investment
	
	Compute and Networking Services
	Storage and Content Delivery Services
	Security and Identity Services
	Database Services
	Analytics Services
	Application Services
	Management Tools
	
	How many ways AWS resources can be managed?
	AWS Management Console
	AWS Command Line Interface (AWS CLI)
	
	provision servers - set up firewall - configure Internet access - allocate & IP addresses - scale your infrastructure to meet increasing demand.
	
	which port number is used in SSH?
	port 22 : Secure Shell (SSH), secure logins, file transfers (scp, sftp) and port forwarding	
	HTTP	80, 8080	TCP	Hyptertext Transfer Protocol. Used by web browsers such as Internet Explorer, Firefox and Opera.
	SSH	22	TCP	Secure Shell protocol. Provides a secure session when logging into a remote machine
	
	
	If you host all your instances in a single location that is affected by such a failure, none of your instances would be available.
	geographical location have region have available zone
	Create EC2 instance in desired regions or Availability Zone
	 
	</h8y>
	<5uy> -Identity and Access Management
	http://aws.amazon.com/iam/
	</5uy>
	<d5k> -cloudwatch
	
	<gen>
	what cloudwatch provides?
	provides monitoring for AWS cloud resources and applications, starting with Amazon EC2. 
	It provides you with visibility into resource utilization, operational performance, and 
	overall demand patterns—including metrics such as CPU utilization, disk reads and writes, and network traffic.
	
	what you can do based on statistics?
	You can get statistics, view graphs, and set alarms for your metric data
	metrics accessed using web service APIs or Command Line Tools
	
	
	how to enable cloudwatch?
	To use Amazon CloudWatch, simply select the Amazon EC2 instances that you’d like to monitor.
	
	can i set custom metrics?
	You can also supply your own business or application metric data
	
	how will you use cloudwatch stored metrics?
	Amazon CloudWatch will begin aggregating and storing monitoring data that can be accessed using web service APIs or Command Line Tools.
	
	
	</gen>
	</d5k>
	<857> -Elastic load balancing
		How to configure and use AWS Elastic Load Balancer & Auto Scaling  https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mMZb52V2Rds
		Elastic load balancing - automatically distribute incoming web traffic across multiple amazon EC2 instances
		A load balancer distributes traffic to multiple instances
		
		steps in setting up load balancer?
		1. define load balancer
		2. Assign security group
		3. Configure health check
		4. Add EC2 instaces
		
		which algorithm is used in the load balancer?
		Round Robin
		
		What are the load balance properties?
		protocol, port no, DNS name, LB name, number of servers assigned
		
		which protocol used for health check and why?
		TCP is used. TCP enables two hosts to establish a connection and exchange streams of data.
		TCP is one of the main protocols in TCP/IP networks. Whereas the IP protocol deals only with packets.
		TCP guarantees delivery of data and also guarantees that packets will be delivered in the same order in which they were sent
		
		
	</857>
	<fgt> -Elastic Beanstalk
	AWS Elastic Beanstalk is a PaaS (Platform as a Service) offered from Amazon Web Services 
	that allows users to create applications and push them to a definable set of AWS services, 
	including Amazon EC2, Amazon S3, Amazon Simple Notification Service (SNS), Amazon CloudWatch, auto scaling, and elastic load balancers.
	</fgt>
	<693> -EC2
	Amazon EC2 - provides virtual servers in the AWS cloud.
	AMI
	<gen>
	key pair when you launch your virtual server
	When you log in to your virtual server, you must present the private key of the key pair to decrypt the login information.
	if windows, download ppk file to connect to EC2 instance using PUTTY
	if linux, download pem file(private key) to connect to EC2 instance using ssh
	</gen>
	</693>
	<254> -VPC & subnet
	subnet -> security, performance
	Amazon VPC - Provides an isolated virtual network for your virtual servers.
	Sub-netting allows for the department to have its own subnetwork.
	subnet - a part of a larger network such as the Internet.
	It speeds up the network
	It provides security
	organize the Depts
	Subnetting allows for the department to have its own subnetwork.
	http://www.chipkin.com/benefits-of-subnets/
	network broadcast domain
	https://www.google.co.in/search?q=router+switch+hub&source=lnms&tbm=isch&sa=X&ved=0CAcQ_AUoAWoVChMI-8mxjI7iyAIVx9saCh2PGAPp&biw=1366&bih=643#imgrc=34YRzLQGg5_40M%3A
	
	A network access control list (ACL) is an optional layer of security that acts as a firewall for controlling traffic in and out of a subnet.
	You might set up network ACLs with rules similar to your security groups in order to add an additional layer of security to your VPC.
	</254>
	<459> -EBS
		1. component failure - backup strategy
		2. provisioned IOPS to reduce latency
		3. suitable for I/O intensive applications- large relational databases
		4. storage backed by SSDs(Solid state drive)
		<gen>
		what is throughput?
			the amount of material or items passing through a system or process
		
		what is latency?
			latency - time taken between sending the request and receiving the response.
		
		what is IOPS?		
			IOPS are input/output operations per second
		
		How EBS protect from component failure?
			Amazon EBS volume is automatically replicated within its Availability Zone - offering high availability and durability.
		
		what can you do with EBS volumes?
			create point-in-time snapshots
			you can create a incremental snapshots based on revisions.
		
		How many ways snapshots can be used?
			you can consider Snapshots for backup strategy
			EC2 instances can be created using a snapshots
			using a single "snapshot" you can create multiple EC2 instances
			you can send sanpshot to another region for geographical expansions
		
		when to use provisioned IOPS and what it's offers?
			Provisioned IOPS (SSD) volumes offer storage with consistent and low-latency performance, 
			and are designed for I/O intensive applications such as large relational or NoSQL databases. 
		
		for what purpose these Provisioned IOPS (SSD) volumes designed for?
			designed for I/O intensive applications such as large relational or NoSQL databases. leverage provisioned IOPS to significantly reduce latency
		
		</gen>
	</459>
	<569> -ECS
	Amazon ECS - Provides Docker containers on virtual servers from Amazon EC2.
	</569>
	<365> -Route 53
	Amazon Route 53 - Routes traffic to your domain name to a resource, such as a virtual server or a load balancer.
	<e34> Create a record in dns
		In the DNS console, expand the Forward Lookup Zones folder for the server you want to work with.
		Right-click the domain you want to update and then from the pop-up menu, choose New Alias. ...
		Type the alias in the Alias Name field.
	for more details, check below link
	https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb727018.aspx
	</e34>
	</365>
	<589> -Lambda
	AWS Lambda - Runs your code on virtual servers from Amazon EC2 in response to events.
	</589>
	<58u> -Auto Scaling
	where to start auto scaling?
	first need to start with configuring the load balancer
	
	in auto scaling how to lanch the new server?
	Create Launch Configuration
	1. Choose AMI
	2. Choose instance type
	3. Configure details
	4. Add storage
	5. Configure security group
	6. Review
	
	https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7SfVZqOVcCI
	avoid single point failure
	load balancer properties : port number, protocol
	<gen>
	Auto Scaling allows you to automatically scale your Amazon EC2 capacity up or down according to conditions you define.
	what are those conditions ?
	
	why scaling?
	to maintain the performance seamlessly
	
	for which application this auto scaling suited ?
	Auto Scaling is particularly well suited for applications that experience hourly, daily, or weekly variability in usage.
	
	how auto scalling is enabled?
	Auto Scaling is enabled by Amazon CloudWatch
	
	</gen>
	</58u>
	<48h> -OpsWorks
		stack - This group of instances is typically called a stack
		Cloud-based computing usually involves groups of AWS resources
		https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cuf7Rqlgeq4
		
		Lifecycle events : set-up - configure - deploy - undeploy - shutdown
		set-up : 			1. sent when instance boots
							2. include deploy event
							3. use for initial installation of softwares & services
		configure event :
							1. sent to all instances when any instances enters or leaves online state
							2. use for making suer the configuration is up to date
		Deploy event : 		sent when you deploy via UI/API, part of each set-up use for custom deployment
							example : deploy from git, artifactory, ftp server
		shut-down event : 	1. sent when an instance is shut down
							2. use for clean shut down
							ex : make a snapshot of something before terminates
	</48h>
	<rt6> -AWS Directory Service
	https://aws.amazon.com/directoryservice/faqs/
	</rt6>
</set-theory>




<45t> Migrate website to Amazon AWS EC2
	Migrate any website to Amazon AWS EC2 in 5 Easy Steps
		The correct way to this is to start route 53. 
		and then make the necessary NS updates both at the domain side and route 53 side. 
		Once done create an A record that will point to your servers.
	Cpanel tool to zip the files and database
	wget http://.../staticweb.zip
	wget http://.../database.zip
	port 80 is open in the security groups
	youtube video https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6eH_XNMUsFQ
</45t>
<5t8> LDAP & single signon
</5t8>
<345> qwiklab
	https://run.qwiklab.com/
	kamalakar312@gmail.com
	Icon@312
	ac : 298010492634
	awsstudent
	k4L4cR25DBH
</345>











